Let's ride.
F1 is a action, drama film directed by Joseph Kosinski.
Racing legend Sonny Hayes is coaxed out of retirement to lead a struggling Formula 1
team—and mentor a young hotshot driver—while chasing one more chance at glory.
Sonny Hayes, played by Brad Pitt.
Joshua Pearce, played by Damson Idris.
Ruben Cervantes, played by Javier Bardem.
Kate McKenna, played by Kerry Condon.
Peter Banning, played by Tobias Menzies.
Kaspar Smolinski, played by Kim Bodnia.
F1 (marketed as F1: The Movie) is a 2025 American sports drama film starring Brad Pitt as Formula One (F1) racing driver Sonny
Hayes, who returns after a 30-year absence to save his former teammate's underdog team, APXGP, from collapse.
The film was directed by Joseph Kosinski from a screenplay by Ehren Kruger.
Damson Idris, Kerry Condon, Tobias Menzies, and Javier
Bardem also star in supporting roles.
Development of the film began in December 2021 with Pitt, Kosinski, Kruger, and producer Jerry Bruckheimer
attached to the project; the latter three had previously collaborated on Top Gun: Maverick (2022).
Supporting cast members were revealed in early 2023, before the start
of principal photography at Silverstone that July.
Filming also took place during Grand Prix weekends of the 2023 and 2024 World
Championships, with the collaboration of the FIA, the governing body of F1.
Racing sequences were adapted from the real-life races, with F1 teams and drivers
appearing throughout, including Lewis Hamilton, who was also a producer.
Hans Zimmer composed the film's score, while numerous
artists contributed to its soundtrack.
F1 premiered at Radio City Music Hall in New York City on June 16, 2025,
and was released in the United States by Warner Bros.
Pictures and Apple Original Films on June 27.
The film received mostly positive reviews from critics for Kosinski's direction, the racing sequences, visuals,
musical score, and the performances of Pitt and Idris, but deemed the screenplay predictable.
F1 grossed $631.8 million worldwide against a $200–300 million budget, becoming the ninth-highest-grossing film of 2025, the
highest-grossing auto racing film of all time, the highest-grossing film by Apple Studios, and the highest-grossing film of Pitt's career.
The National Board of Review named it as one of the top ten films of the year.
At the 98th Academy Awards, it received four
nominations, including Best Picture.
The film explores themes of comeback, racing, race car
driver, sport competition, beforecreditsstinger.
The tone is emotional.